Now that you know how to start the ROS master and are able to run nodes,
ROS マスターの開始とノードの実行方法を理解したので
you can begin to investigate the topics and messages
turtlesim ノードと turtle teleop キーノードに関する
associated with the turtlesim node and the turtle teleop key nodes.
トピックとメッセージの調査が開始できます
We'll be picking up this discussion from where we left off in the last screencast,
この話題を前回のスクリーンキャストで中断した部分から始めます
which is to say roscore,
つまり roscore
turtlesim node, and the turtle teleop key nodes are all running.
turtlesim ノード turtle teleop キーノードすべてが実行中の状態です
Let's investigate exactly what's going on behind the scenes.
背後で何が行われているのか 調査してみましょう
If you had just stumbled upon this running system,
この実行中のシステムを偶然見つけた場合
you might be inclined to ask the question, which nodes are running?
どのノードが実行中なのか 疑問に思うのではないでしょうか?
To answer this you would open a new terminal and use the command rosnode list.
これに答えるため 新しいターミナルを開き rosnode list コマンドを使用します
This command will query the ROS master for a list of all of
このコマンドでは システム上のすべてのアクティブノードのリストを
the active nodes on the system and print them to the console.
ROS マスターに問い合わせ コンソールへ出力します
And there we have it, a list of three nodes running on the system.
出力結果はこちら システムで実行中のノードのリストが表示されました
Two of these nodes should look relatively familiar as we
これら 2 つのノードには見覚えがあるはずです
launched them explicitly just a moment ago. But what's the third?
明らかにちょうど少し前に起動したものですねでは 3 つめのノードは何でしょうか?
ROSout is a node that's automatically launched by the ROS master.
ROSout とは 自動的に ROS マスターが起動したノードです
It's responsible for aggregating,
働きとしては ログメッセージの集約
filtering, and recording log messages to a text file.
フィルタリング そして記録をテキストファイルとして実行することです
We'll learn more about that one later in upcoming projects where we will
この後のプロジェクトでは ROS メッセージによるエクスペリエンスを得ながら
be getting hands on experience with ROS log messages.
このことについてさらに学習していきます